这可太酷了
This is so cool.
-我们错过什么了吗?-他们肯定还得再跑11圈呢
-Did we miss anything? -They've got like 11 laps to go.
我们得找个地方好让,他经过的时候能看见标语
We gotta find a good place where he can see the signwhen he goes by.
等等，孩子
wait up,kids!
第六转弯处
Turn six.
快走
Come on!
那里，那上边
That's it,up there.
你能看见什么吗?
Can you see anything?
你带他的喷雾器了吗?
Did you bring his inhaler?
哦，该死，落车里了
Oh,crap. I think it's in the car.
我去拿
I'll go get it.
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
你爸马上就回来
Your dad's gonna be right back.
我能看见他，他就在前面
I can see him. He's right up front.
甜心，你喘的挺厉害
Honey,you're wheezing.
他们来了
Here they come!
冲啊，杰
Go,jeff,yeah!
你是第一
You're number one!
他的样子不太好啊
He doesn't look so good.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
哦，主啊，你怀孕了吗?
Oh,god. Are you pregnant?
因为我真想上完高中
Because I really want to finish high school.
哦，你得更新你的信任状
Oh. You have to renew your credential.
他们在两个月内依然是有效的
They're good for two more months.
是三周，而且文件运转很慢的
Three weeks,and the paperwork takes forever.
你的申请表
Your application.
你的玩忽职守保险
Your malpractice insurance.
犯罪纪律检查
Criminal records check.
而且你知道那会需要你做些解释的
And you know that's gonna take some explaining.
你知道，我们的关系比我们,在一起睡的时候要好的多
You know,our relationship was way better when we were sleeping together.
我们干嘛不那么干了呢？,你结婚了吗？
Why did we stop doing that? Did you get married?
对啊，否则呢我不是你米饭上的红点了？
Yeah. Otherwise I'd be on you like red on rice.
米饭不……
Rice isn't--
哦，我明白了
oh,I get it.
你的口述进度也慢了
You're also behind on your dictations.
我不做口述
I don't do dictations.
卡梅伦的事，或者其他什么人做
Cameron does them. Or somebody.
你不能让你唯一的女性雇员,干你的行政工作
You can't have your sole female employee doing your clerical work,
因为你该注意那样会符合性骚扰的条件
which you'd know if you'd attended the required sexual harassment seminars.
我会因为你骚扰逮到个休息的机会
Now I'm gonna pause so you can make a crack about harassment.
玩笑杀手
Joke killer.
豪斯
house.
有病人了
Got a patient.
对不起，不能再玩了
Sorry. Can't play anymore.
我妈在叫我
My mom's calling me.
我们刚接诊了一位世界级骑手
We just admitted a world-class cyclist.
你挺热心啊
You've gotta fire stacy.
对，没错
Yeah,I'll get right on that.
弗杰
Jeff forster.
每小时30公里时呼吸停止
Respiratory arrest at 30 miles per hour.
她正拿一堆文件来烦我
She's loading me up with pointless paperwork.
好吧，或许是你拖延了那些无聊的文件
Well,you're way behind on your pointless paperwork.
两次停跳……
O2 stats are in the--
她很敌对
she's hostile.
你了解我，敌意会让我退缩……
You know me. Hostility makes me shrink up like a--
我想不出无性的比喻方式
I can't think of a non-sexual metaphor.
她要拿把尺站在我的桌边检查我的拼写
She's gonna stand over my desk with a ruler checking my spelling.
急诊已经检查了肺渗透，没什么
Er checked for lung infiltrates. Nothing there.
专业运动员，卡迪
Professional athletes,cuddy.
就象在两点看老电影一样
It's like watching an old movie at 2:00 A.M.
旧梦重温
Reliving all the classic moments.
一部分是他否认是毒品
The part where he denies it's drugs.
一部分是好人进来，证明是毒品
The part where the good guys ride in tests a'blazing,prove that it is drugs.
奥斯卡式的表演
Oscar clip.
他无法想像那些东西怎么进入他身体的
He can't imagine how they got into his body.
多熟悉，多令人安慰啊
It's so familiar,so comforting.
她无法应付与我一起工作
She can't handle working with me.
哦，是啊，对
Oh,right. Yeah.
她还对你有意，所以无法应付
She's still got a thing to you,making it impossible for her to deal.
理由完美，除了代词
Makes perfect sense. Except for the pronouns.
无论如何，谢谢你把我从,那个会面里拯救出来
Anyway,thanks for getting me out of that meeting.
他没否认毒品
He's not denying the drugs.
我觉得他是真病了
I'm thinking he's actually sick.
－杰弗，这是……,－我是医生
Jeff forster,this is-- I'm a doctor.
你是病人
You're a sick person.
而你……是爱人
And you... are a loved one.
其实，是经纪人，我们在一起7年了
Actually,manager. We've been together for seven years.
那么到底现在药物在比赛中,是发挥什么功效呢?
So what's the drug du jour on the bike circuit these days?
促进红细胞生成吗?
Still erythropoietin?
还是用迷幻药加油?
Or you guys just chugging battery acid?
我不碰epo
There's no way I'd touch epo.
太多人被发现或者死掉
Too many guys stroking out and dying.
该死
Damn!
10块钱的票，6块钱的爆米花
Ten bucks for the ticket,six for the popcorn.
我直接做血液注射
I do straight blood doping.
情节变复杂了
Plot twist.
那是个大胆的坦白
That's a very daring confession.
我们是要保密的，对吧?
We've got confidentiality,right?
假如我比你的顾客更有道德的话
Assuming I'm more ethical than your client.
那么，为了乐趣和获益而,注射捐赠者的血红细胞
So,injecting yourself with donor red blood cells for fun and profit.
你袖子里还有别的把戏吗?
Any other tricks up your sleeve?
最近没有了
Well,nothing much recently.
我来是为了一个慈善比赛，赢了也无所谓
I'm in town for a charity ride,so it didn't matter if I won.
孩子们需要看到我
The kids just needed to see me.
如果你骑点，他们还能看你长一点
If you go slower,they see you longer.
我们的身体会受上朔至上周五的影响
Let's say that our health could be affected by things we did before last friday.
嗯...
Well...
嗯，我通常会睡高压氧仓
um,I usually sleep in a hyperbaric chamber.
我会用静脉点滴注射电解液
I've been pumping up electrolytes with an iv drip.
服用合成代谢药，安非他明，利尿剂
Anabolic herbal supplements,amphetamines,and diuretics.
对，对，那你是为什么生病的呢?
Yeah,yeah,yeah. But why would you be sick?
我知道点滴有风险
I know that doping has risks.
我知道那有悖规则
I know that it'soutside the rules.
但是我得在工作中有所作为
But I do what I have toto kick ass at my job.
难道不是吗?
Don't you?
豪斯医生相信保守的努力工作
Dr. House isa firm believer in good old-fashionedhard work.
这家伙连普通的病都不得
This guy doesn't even get sicklike a regular person.
只有一些无来由的症状,
Instead of a listof symptoms and no cause,
而我们只有一个症状的可能成因
we have a list of possiblecauses for one symptom.
症状是死亡吗?
Is the symptom death?
呼吸不畅
Respiratory distress.
精神错乱不是成因，我查过了
And insanity doesn'tcause it. I looked it up.
是点滴
It's the doping.
注射多余的红血球可以提高耐久力水平
Injecting extra red cellsboots your endurance level,
但也可以使血液浓稠度提高
but it alsothickens your blood.
血液变稠可变成凝块而使呼吸受阻
Thick blood equals clotsequals respiratory distress.
有清洁螺旋胸部ct就不同了
Not with a clean spiralchest ct.
这家伙在高压氧仓睡觉
Guy's sleepingin an hyperbaric chamber.
过度供养可导致细胞毁损,如果毁损细胞在肺部……
Over-oxygenation cancause cell damage,and if the cellsin the lungs are damaged--
会导致肺水肿，但他却没有
that'd causepulmonary edema,which he doesn't have.
他所用的补养品含育亨宾,可导致神经瘫痪
The supplements he's beentaking contain yohimbe,which can causenerve paralysis.
总氧化值正常
Tox screen was normal.
所有的测试都正常
All the tests were normal.
没有肿块、腺体瘤，但他依然无法呼吸
There's no clot,no edema,and yet he still can'tbreathe.
所以有我们没看见的东西
So there's somethingin here that we can't see.
哦，空气
Oh. Air.
到爸爸这来吧
Come to papa.
这家伙一直都给自己注射，多少次一天？
This guy's been injectinghimself how many times a day?
只是针头一个小的疏忽,就可导致空气栓塞
All it'd take is oneslip of the needle to cause an air embolus.
于是空气阻碍了他呼吸空气
So air is keeping himfrom breathing air.
我们就当它是个讽刺吧
Let's go with that for the irony.
取VQ扫描仪来检查气泡吧
Get a vq scan and checkhis veins for bubbles.
氙气133
Xenon 133.
其放射性足以使我们,能够追踪在你肺部的空气运动
It's just radioactive enough for us to track the airmoving through your lungs.
我的意外上新闻了吗?
My accident on the news?
对，没准要闹上个一个星期呢
Yeah. You madeplays of the week.
再加把劲，自行车就跟赛车一样风尚了
Few more of those and cycling will beas popular as nascar.
我们注射类似的东西进去以观察它的流动
We inject similar stuffinto your blood so we can watch itcirculate.
那么如果你不小心地注射了一个气泡进去
Now if you accidentallyinjected a bubble,
那我们就可以看到空气流通顺畅,但血液流动吃力
we'll see good air flowbut poor blood flow.
嗯，我现在很小心了，伙计
Un-huh.I'm careful,man.
还有应有的尊重，伙计
With all due respect,man,
我怀疑你对自己还有没有错的事情没做过
I doubt there's anythingwrong with you that you didn't doto yourself.
肿瘤科有个孩子，她床头有杰的照片
There's this kidin oncology. She's got a pictureof jeff above her bed.
超级米奇是个酒鬼
Mickey mantlewas an alcoholic.
至少他赢了家乡的比赛
At least he hithis own home runs.
他也不自己吃有毒的东西
He didn't physicallyalter himself.
我们去药店是想入睡或保持清醒
We take drugsto help us fall asleep,to stay awake.
我们又不靠看谁能清醒最久论事业成败
We don't make careers out of who can stayawake the longest.
真的？你上过……嗯,不知道，医科大学吗？
Really? Ever been to,oh,I don't know,med school?
伙计们，他是为生计比赛,谁管呢？
Uh,guys,he plays a gamefor a living. Who cares?
你根本就不看体育台
You don't even like sports.
他赚了上百万的钱欺骗拥护者
He's making millionsof dollars ripping off fans.
任何人觉得该为一个人
Anyone who thinks they should pay a guy money
扔球甚远，或蹬脚甚快而付钱
because he can throw a ball really far,
都该被骗
or pedal really fast deservesto be ripped off.
没错，愚蠢，愚蠢的小孩
Yeah,stupid,stupid kids.
我曾有个叔叔能把樱桃核吐50码远
I've got an uncle. He can spit a cherry pit50 yards.
他在商店兼职卖润滑油,生活不公
He's working part-time ata lube shop. Life isn't fair.
或许是
Maybe it is.
你是对的
you were right.
这三个字是浪费
Now there wentthree wasted words.
他的肺部是有气泡
There is a bubblein his lung.
我们该做个导入检查
We should do a swan-ganzcatheterization.
我喜欢你把两人的话一个人都说了
I love when you do both sidesof the conversation.
象白噪音一样，很平和
It's like white noise.It's very peaceful.
是不是我一吃饭就有灯亮啊?
Is there a lightsomewhere that goes on when I have food?
绿色是食物，黄色是饮料,红色是不洁的念头
Green for food,orange for beverages,red for impure thoughts.
大胡子两星期出来一次
That bulb burns outevery two weeks.
你的骑手怎么样了?
How's your biker?
静脉管里泵进去一个气泡
Pumped an air bubble into a vein in his lung.
都是人为的，点滴什么的
The things people do.Doping. Vicodin.
嘿，你在说我呢，对吧？
Hey. You're talkingabout me,aren't you?
我只是在形式职责,而他是想赢更多的奖项
I'm just tryingto function. He's trying to win himselfsome little yellow jerseys.
哦，什么?
Uh-oh.What?
天堂的麻烦，两点的位置
Trouble in paradise,two o'clock.
你两点还是我两点?
Your two o'clockor my two o'clock?
那里
There.
她看上去挺高兴的
She seems perfectly happy.
很明显，他们在你没机会后,把个马戏表演搞的挺有声色
Obviously,they huddledin the hall and worked upthis circus act on the off-chanceyou'd be in here.
她三小时前很生气来着
She was unbelievably pissythree hours ago.
跟你生气，跟她丈夫挺高兴
Hmm. Pissy with you.Happy with her husband.
对，而且只有一个合理的解释
Yes,there could only be onepossible explanation for that.
她生气的时候就讽刺人
When she's angry,she gets sarcastic.
而苦恼的时候就很有趣
When's she annoyed,she's funny.
但当她失败的时候就很生气
But when she's frustrated,she gets pissy.
是，我还能跟上你
Yes,yes,I'm with you so far.
她跟马克在一起时糟透了，因为他不是我
She's miserable with mark because he's not me.
所以她要把我改变的不象我
So she's gotta makeme not me,
所以她把我的专业生涯弄的不成样
so she makes my professionallife miserable.
如果我不能尽职……
If I can't do my job--
你真的，真得找点什么了
you really,reallyneed to get some.
哦，我老能找到什么的
Oh,I get some "some"all the time.
那就是我老需要借钱的原因
That's why I always needto borrow some money.
嗨，詹姆
Hi,james.
格里，你可一定要做那个文件呦?
Greg.Gotten to that paperwork?
我太忙了
I've been busy.
什么?
Pardon me?
我太忙了
I've been busy.
你救人命后，他们永远欠你的
When you savesomeone's life,they owe you forever.
说的对
You're right.
带上斯黛希吧
Take stacy.
哦，等等
Oh,wait.
她恐怕还是会离开你的
She'd probably justleave you all over again.
你恢复的怎样?
How's your recovery going?
小肌肉长出来了吗?
Gotten aroundto the small muscles yet?
你知道跟肌肉的尺寸无关
You know,it's notthe size of the muscle.
跟放的地方有关
It's whereyou get to put it.
天啊，象在三年级,看王尔德的《圣诞胆小鬼》一样
My goodness. It's likewatching oscar wilde and noel cowardin the third grade.
请原谅
Excuse us.
多怪啊?
How awkward was that?
他跑这来到底干什么啊?
What's he doing here anyway?
他周二和周五做理疗
He's got physio tuesdaysand fridays.
马克参加给残疾人做的小组心理治疗
Uh,mark is ingroup therapy for people copingwith disability.
他本想药物成瘾
He was thinking aboutdeveloping a drug addiction,
可那多愚蠢
but that would be stupid.
嘿，你……你又来了
Hey,you're--you again.
不开马克做心理治疗的玩笑吗?
Not gonna make some joke about mark being in therapy?
有什么可说的?
What's there to say?
他在做负责任的事情
He's doingthe responsible thing.
我确信他要应对的还多着呢
I'm sure he's gota lot to deal with.
你让我紧张
You're making me nervous.
每当有个运动员倒下,你们就以为是毒品的事
every time an athlete goes down,you guys assume it's drugs.
看，医生说可能是药反流
Look,the doctors sayits probably acid reflux.
对，明天打给我,他能出院的可能性很大
Yeah,look,call me tomorrow. There's a good chance he'll be released.
好，再见
Okay. Bye-bye.
这样说合适吗?
So is this fixing him?
如果他的药反流不比我们想的差的话
If his acid reflux isn'tworse than we thought,yeah.
我四天内得赶到西班牙
I've gotta be in spainin four days.
不该成问题
Shouldn't be a problem.
太好了
Great.
只要我找到那个小坏蛋就可以把它吸出来
If I can just findthe little bugger,I should be ableto suck it out.
我的腿觉得很虚弱
Hmm. My legs feel weak.
你在中级镇静条件下做试验
You're under mild sedationfor the test.
会逐渐减弱
It'll wear off.
那里
There it is.
嗯，逮到了
Ah. Got it.
哦，太好了，我来收拾他的东西
Oh,fantastic.I'll pack his things.
还不行，我要监测他几个小时,确保他没事
Not yet. I want to monitor himfor a couple of hours. Make sure he's okay.
给他时间给我签字，没准是件运动衫呢
Give him time to signa picture for me. Maybe even a jersey.
"给蔡大夫，我欠你太多了"
"To dr. Chase,I owe you everything."
不必那么私人化吧
It doesn't have tobe that personal.
易趣上没那么多叫“蔡大夫”的是吧?
Oh. Not too many ebay shoppersnamed dr. Chase,huh?
还想得那个吐口水大奖呢
Still trying to unloadthe barbara walters spit cup.
给你这个
here you go.
认真的，什么都行
Seriously,anything's fine.
杰?
Jeff?
你没事吧?
You all right?
杰，你能吞咽吗?
Jeff,can you swallow?
什么让一个家伙开始流口水
What makes a guy,start drooling?
Chace，你穿内裤了吗?
Chase,were you wearingyour short shorts?
他的脖子和腭部肌肉无力
Muscle fatiguein his neck and jaw.
－他肯定有比空气栓塞更严重的问题,－为什么？
He's obviously got somethingworse than an air embolus. Why?
因为肺不会流口水啊
Because you don't droolfrom your lungs.
也许问题不是栓塞本身
Maybe the problem'snot the embolus itself.
也许是治疗的问题
Maybe it's the treatment.
也许你伤到了神经，看上去
Maybe you hit a nerve.Literally.
栓子切除术很干净
The embolectomy was clean.
他的腿很疲倦
His legs were tired too.
我以为是镇静作用，如果不是
I thought it was fromthe sedation,but if not,
那就是全身性的
it means he's gotsomething systemic.
意思就是说跟他的营养药无关了
Which means it wouldhave nothing to do with the stuntshe's been pulling.
狼疮或者是多肌炎
Lupus or polymyositis.
那可以解释肌肉无力
It explains the progressivemuscle weakness.
着地无力？
It could be als.
太年轻了不会
He's too young for that.
某种肌肉营养不足?
Some type of muscular dystrophy?
岁数够大了不会
He's too old for that.
那到底是什么呢，喇叭花?
So what would bejust right,goldilocks?
全面的血液检查，包括狼疮的ANA监测
full blood workup,including ana for lupus.
同时做肌肉活检
And get a muscle biopsy.
看看到底是肌肉的问题,还是神经系统的问题
Find out if we're talkingmyopathy or neuropathy.
我开会晚了
I'm late for my session.
开会?
Session?
是程序的一部分
It's all a partof the process.
你会生气，然后……
You get angryand then you get--
对，我正合这个程序
yeah,I'm right on schedule.
那么什么时候才能结束呢?
So when am I gonna be done?
不，我需要知道因为我有计划
No,I need to know because I've gotplans to make.
我的意思是，我什么时候能预定壁球比赛?
I mean,when can I safelybook a game of squash?
我什么时候能不生气?
When am I gonna stop being angry?
不是今天
Not today.
我做康复治疗
I've comefor the healing.
哈医生，你知道
Dr. Harper,as you know,
我，嗯，有条坏腿
I,uh--ahem.I have a bum leg.
但是你不知道我对它很生气
What you don't know is I'm upset about it.
我需要倾诉
I need to talk.
你了解豪斯，你知道我们有过节
-You know house. -You know we have a history.
你跟我说过多年我该参加
You've been telling me for yearsthat I should come by.
我来了
Here I am.
大家好
Hi,guys.
周四有小组
got a thursday group.
打扑克
Poker night.
周一上午?
Monday morning?
读书会
Book club.
嗯，你看，如果有问题……
Well,look,if it's a problem,
我干脆离开，自己对付我的愤怒去好了
I'll just go dealwith my rage privately.
等等
Wait.
如果你俩能解决这种紧张气氛,你们真的可以互相帮助
If you two could resolvethis tension,you could reallyhelp each other.
我懒得争吵
I'm tired of fighting.
看来除非我同意要么我就是混蛋喽?
So either I say yesor I'm the jerk?
哦，上帝，我知道那种感觉
Oh,god,I knowthat feeling.
我从杰的大腿取了样本
I took the muscle specimenfrom jeff's thigh.
我猜那是我们能发现问题的最佳机会了
I figured that's wherewe'd have the best chance at finding something.
也是最疼的切入点
And the most painfulplace to cut into.
我猜是无咖啡因的
I assume that's caffeine-free.
不能人工增加你的性能
Wouldn't want to be artificiallyboosting your performance.
别再惹她了
Don't start her up again.
咖啡因是合法的
Caffeine's legal.
都是规矩的事，对吧?
All about the rules,eh?
只是个自行车比赛
It's a bike race.
都是由委员们定的
A completely arbitraryset of rules that everyone complies withfor no other reason
武断的规矩决定他们得遵守
than that some committeesays that they should.
但是那就是关键，那就是比赛
But that's the point. That's what the game is.
所以，如果你违背了武断的规定,卡梅伦就要你下地狱
So if you breakan arbitrary rule,cameron damns you to hell,
但如果你破坏的规矩是设计来保护人们的
but if you break a rulethat actually has a reason,that's designedto protect people,
卡梅伦就会疯狂地爱上你
cameron developsa crazy crush on you.
豪斯并没刻意打扮自己
House doesn't pretendto be some golden boy.
他是想帮助别人，不是美化自己
He does it to help people,not to glorify himself.
那你干嘛不向自行车专家举报杰?
So why don't you report jeff to the biking authorities?
嗯，道德规范
Um,ethics.
嗯，你不是要美化自己
Well,you wouldn'tbe doing it to glorify yourself.
你是想建立美好社会
You'd just be tryingto make a better world.
至少你还能自理
At least you can stillget around on your own.
对，我知道
Yeah,I know.
但你正开始重新站立
But you'restarting to walk.
你会好起来
You're gonna get better.
你有职业，可以有所作为
You have a job,a way to be productive.
你有妻子
You have a wife.
那更有意义?
Which givesgreater meaning?
妻子可以使事情更复杂，我想
A wife could make thingsharder,too,I suppose.
这跟斯黛希无关
This isn't about stacy.
当我出事时，斯黛希表现很好
When it happened to me,stacy was great.
她一直让我不要太急躁
She kept telling menot to rush it.
但我从不相信她
But I never believed her.
她很真诚
She means it.
我知道，但...
I know,but...
斯黛希...
stacy...
她不必等，对吧?
she didn'thave to wait,right?
而且你也知道她有同感
And you knowshe feels it too.
就是在工作上花更多时间,从工作中得到更多满足
Means more time at work,means more satisfaction from work.
她并不是要结婚作保姆的
She didn't get marriedto be a nursemaid.
她需要一个男人
She wants a man.
他怎么会爱一个象你这样,操纵别人的混蛋？
How the hellcould she have loved a manipulativeson of a bitch like you?
那是个有趣的问题
That's an interesting question.
也许她被我俩之间不同的东西所吸引
Maybe she was attractedto different things in the two of us.
她背离了你
She left you.
那又为什么跟我重新开始关系?
Then why was she with meto begin with?
她犯了个错
She made a mistake.
或许就那么简单
Maybe it's that simple.
又或许是她看到我身上有你没有的东西
Or maybe she sawsomething in me,something she doesn'tget from you.
我不是混蛋
I'm not an ass.
或许她需要个混蛋，显然她曾有过一个
Maybe she wanted an ass.She obviously did once.
要么他走要么我走
Either he goes or I go.
你以为那是你关掉就可以解决的吗?
You think that's the kind ofthing you can just turn off?
把他轰走
Get him out of here!
豪斯医生，取消你的读书会
Dr. House,cancel your book group.
你周一来
You're coming on mondays.
我有新理论
Here's my new theory.
流口水是另一个竞争优势
The drooling's another competitive edge.
没人能在他后面跑，因为路面太滑
Nobody can draft behind him.Road gets slick.
他是唯一一个不在雨天比赛的人
He's the only onenot racing in the rain.
他几乎不能挪动手脚
He can barely movehis arms or legs.
瘫痪?
Paralysis?
不，是全面的虚弱
No,justgeneral weakness.
肌肉活检显示多肌炎测试阴性
Muscle biopsy is negativefor polymyositis.
ALS和肌肉营养失调都不对
And als.And muscle dystrophy.
狼疮的ＡＮＡ监测也是阴性
ana for lupus also negative.
也许是他的骑手短裤太紧了
maybe his bike shorts were just on too tight.
那么按照你的原理，豪斯不该用拐棍
So by your rationale,house shouldn't use a cane.
他该象上帝所意愿的那样拖着他的坏腿？
He should just drag his bumleg around as god intended?
豪斯有障碍
house has a handicap.
他的发泄方式是正常的
All he's aiming foris normality.
那由谁来决定是否正常?
and who decides what's normal?
我们发明一种可以,令人类活多２０年的药又如何?
What if we find a drug that makes people live 20 years longer?
我们该因为那不正常就禁止吗?
Should we ban thatbecause it's not normal?
杰并不是要正常，他要超能力
Jeff doesn't want normal. He wants super powers.
那他又为什么正常呢?
So why is he normal?
哦，上帝啊，你也来吗？
Oh,god. You too?
他因出色而遭枪毙啊
He's shooting for extraordinary.
干嘛所有事都非得平凡呢？
So why is everythingso ordinary?
我是说，这家伙呼吸、喝酒
I mean,this guy'sbreathing,drinking,
注射他能找到的一切
and injecting himselfwith everything he can find
来增强他身体的化学指标,但一切检查都那么正常
to amp up his body chemistry,and yet every test is normal.
他人为提高血红细胞含量,但又为什么没增加呢?
He's artificially raisinghis red blood count,so why isn't it raised?
也许已经提高了
Maybe his count is raised.
也许已经正常到药检局可以搞他的地步了
Maybe what's normal for usis out of whack for him.
什么也瞒不了你
Can't slip a anythingby you.
如果是事实，那么他的白血球也增加了
well,if that's true,his white cells are up too,
那就意味着有感染
which would point tosome kind of infection.
肌肉虚弱、极度虚弱
Muscle weakness,exhaustion.
可能是脑炎
He could have encephalitis.
那是长程的
That's kind of a long shot.
一个多小时了,该用尖利的东西戳病人了
But it's been over an hour since we poked the patientwith something sharp,
那么做腰椎穿刺吧
so get a lumbar puncture.
再申请广谱抗生素
And order broad-spectrumantibiotics.
不，跟评价无关
no,it's not about judging.
但安排约会你该提供照片啊
It's just thaton a dating service you should post a photo.
我得走了
I have to go.
我很抱歉打扰你
I'm so sorryto bother you.
没关系，我……是会计
No,not a problem.I was just,uh...accounting.
我是弗杰的经纪人
I'm jeff forster's manager.
他已经在这一天了，但还是没有任何诊断
He's been here a whole dayand it doesn't seem like we're any closerto a diagnosis.
弗杰，一整天了吗?
Jeff forster.A whole day,huh?
嗯，我是想看看是否,我可以使事情加速进行
Mm-hmm.I was just wondering if I could helpspeed things up.
你的客户做了肌肉活检
Your client's hada muscle biopsy,
全套血液检查
a full blood workup,
而且他还约了明天上午的腰椎穿刺
and he's scheduledfor a lumbar puncture at 10:00 A.M. Tomorrow.
杰是卢卡的队员
Jeff is in the lucas wing.
如果卢卡先生需要做个腰椎穿刺,他需要等到明天上午吗？
If mr. Lucas showed upneeding a lumbar puncture,would he have to waituntil tomorrow?
卢卡先生已经死了
Mr. Lucas is dead.
好，这是个开始
Good. Then there'san opening.
杰过去尽全力争当第一，对吧？
Jeff is used to doing whatever he has toto be first,isn't he?
那对他很有利
It's been verylucrative for him.
他觉得他应该尽量回馈
He feels it's importantthat he give something back.
我听说你象扩充你的核药物研究部门
I hear you've beenraising funds for your nuclearmedicine department.
或者管他呢
Or whatever.
谢谢大家，干的这么晚
Thank you,guys,for working so late.
很高兴到这
Glad to be here.
腰椎穿刺会告诉我们发生了什么事
The lumbar puncture will tell us what kind of infection you've got.
同时我们给抗生素
In the meantime,we're administering antibiotics.
你喜欢当英雄是吧?
Do you like being a hero?
那是生计
It's a living.
你不感到有责任吗?
You don't feel a senseof responsibility?
外面有不少孩子崇拜你
There's kids out therethat worship you.
在我巡回比赛时
When I was a rookieon the tour,
我收到威斯康辛的一个人的信
I got a letter from a guy in wisconsin
他要我给他儿子发信
who wanted me to senda note to his son.
说他崇拜我
Said he worshipped me.
你知道崇拜的意思吗?
You know what"worship" means?
我查过
I looked it up.
意思是：不容置疑的、不予评价的爱
It means to love...unquestioningly and uncritically.
而那个孩子根本不认识我,
So the kid doesn't even know me,
但他不容置疑的、不予评价的爱我
but he loves meunquestioningly and uncritically.
所以你决定占个便宜？
So you decided to takeadvantage of that.
那我该怎么做?
What should I have done?
"亲爱的先生,
"Dear sir,
"我只是个自行车骑的不错的家伙
"I'm just a guy who ridesa bike pretty good.
你和你儿子疯了吗"?
You and your kidare out of your minds"?
我的胳膊感觉奇怪
My arms feel funny.
他的呼吸器掉了，呼吸停止
His sats are dropping.He's in respiratory arrest.
他不会的，我们固定好了
He can't be.We fixed that.
显然没有
Apparently not.
幸好我们治好了他的呼吸停止
so glad we cured his respiratory arrest.
不加呼吸器就会呼吸停止
Freed him up to developrespiratory arrest.
脑炎测试阴性
Lp was negativefor encephalitis.
白血球数量正常
the white count'sstill the same,
红血球数量减至29%
but the red count'sfallen to 29%.
我昨天的理论是什么?
What was my the ory yesterday?
我搞砸了栓子清楚术
That I screwed upthe embolectomy.
我们做个胸部X光片检查
We'll get a chestx-ray to check.
我没搞砸，你干嘛……
I didn't screw up.Why would you--
你怎么能这么可怜呢，小蔡，,他都下降了一品脱
how can you beso petty,chase? He's down a quart.
他失血要不就是因为你伤到他,
Either he's losing bloodbecause you nicked something,
要不就是他停止造血，如果那样的话,我们说的就是贫血造成的肌肉失效
or he's just notproducing blood,in which place we're talkingacute anemia combined with a muscular disorder.
肾上腺综合症?
Paraneoplastic syndrome?
要么就是你搞砸了,要么就是他得了癌症
Either you screwed upor he's got cancer.
我觉得我该开始抽烟了
I think I should startsmoking again.
你的那个结论需要一个医学支持吗?
You want a medical opinionsupporting that decision?
我一戒除症状就开始
The symptoms startedas soon as I quit.
症状的意思是...
Symptoms meaning...
腹泻，老腹泻
diarrhea. A lot of diarrhea.
一天10到12次，太尴尬了
Ten or twelve times a day.It's really embarrassing.
我是飞行服务生……
I'm a flight attendantand--
往上点，我的打嗝停止了
on the upside,my hiccups are gone.
你去过他的小组治疗了
You went to his group.
都是你曾说的,“格里，你该面对你的感觉”
You were the one who was all,"greg,you needto confront your feelings."
那是五年前的事
That was five years ago.
嗯，我很生气
Well,I've been pissy.
好，你不想接受帮助,那就是说别人也甭想喽？
Fine. You don't want help. Does that meannobody should get it?
马克寻求帮助是为什么呢? 他很愤怒吗?
Mark's looking for help because what? He's resentful?
挫败感？我是因为关心才问的
Overwhelmed?I'm asking because I care.
不是针对他，你还对我有邪念,所以你不管是谁的婚姻……
Not about him.You still want to jump me,so you don't carewhose marriage--
听着，我可以随时卸掉包袱的
listen,I can getmy rocks off any time I want.
我不能应付的是,你在我的工作中到处找我麻烦
What I don't seem to beable to do is my job without you hangingover my shoulder.
一天几盒?
How many packs?
一天一盒多点，是清型的，而且我戒了
A bit over one a day,but they were lightsand I quit.
你曾跟她交往吗?
You used to go outwith her?
是啊，我在想什么呢?
Yeah. What was I thinking?
我是在说你正嚼着的替代香口胶
I'm talking aboutthe gum you're chewing to replace smokingas an oral fixation.
多少块?
How many packs?
六块，或者七块
Six,maybe seven.
我想保护你
I'm trying to protect you.
卡迪和我或许是想制止你跳崖的……
Cuddy and I may be the only people stopping youfrom jumping off a cliff...
-你呕气,-不是，我生气,-呕气
-you're pissy. -No,I am angry. -Pissy.
你失败的时候就呕气
You get pissywhen you're frustrated.
-闭嘴,-好吧，我错了
-Shut up. -Okay,I'm wrong.
这对马克来说难度非比寻常,你该知道的
This is unbelievablydifficult for mark,which you should know.
而你该比旁人更能理解
Which you should be ableto summon up some level of empathy for.
没错，一对瘸子,我们该成立个乐队组合
Right. The crippled boys.We should start a band.
我跟马克相处融洽
I have a good thingwith mark.
我们尽全力对待这个事件
We are handling thisthe best way we know how.
而这些与我无关?
And none of this hasanything to do with me?
没有，除非是你不想也不让它过去,让它过去
No,nothing. Except that you can'tor won't just let it go. Let it go.
你被下毒了
You're being poisoned.
香口胶吗?
By gum?
无糖口香糖用山梨酸产生甜味
Sugarless gum usessorbitol as a sweetener.
我们用山梨酸作为缓泻剂
We use sorbitolas a laxative.
这可以证明他是否有血癌?
This'll tell you if he'sgot cancer in his blood?
如果有在骨髓内可看到变异细胞
If he does,we'll seeabnormal cells in the marrow.
检查需要多少时间?
How long willthe test take?
我会尽快
I'll get them inas soon as I can.
如果没癌,
And if doesn'thave cancer,
会是什么?
what else could it be?
可能是早前给他做测试带来的伤害
It's possiblesome damage was done during one of the testswe gave him.
所以要么是你的医生搞砸了简单的检查,要么是他得癌了？
So eitherone of your doctors screwed upa simple procedure,or he's got cancer.
在活检报告出来前我们什么都不能确定
We can't knowanything for sure until the biopsy comes back.
有点刺痛，我知道
It stings,I know.
不，他要把管子拔出来
No,he wants the tube out.
不行，杰
Can't do that,jeff.
如果你想说话只能写出来了
If you want to say something,you've got to write it down.
好吗?
Okay?
这里,（是我自己导致的吗？）
Here.
如果是癌症，有可能
If it's cancer,it's possible.
还不得而知
There's no way to know for sure.
电话坏了吗?
Phone not working?
一个太平间服务员让我给你这个
One of the morgue attendantsasked me to bring this to you.
奇怪他们找我干嘛？
I wonder whythey're calling me.
对，我也是
Yeah,me too actually.
是，我也奇怪为什么《时代》周刊,为什么会回复你的电话？
I was why the times was returning your call.
你是医生还是自行车警察?
You a doctoror the bicycle police?
他骗人
He's cheating.
他不该得逞
He shouldn't get away with it.
你已经告诉他们什么了吗?
Have you actually told them anything yet?
你是担心先例吗?
You worriedabout the precedent?
我担心你
I'm worried about you.
你要告发我吗?
You gonna turn me in?
不会
No.
他犯了错
He's made a mistake.
揭露真相并不能逆转已做的
Revealing the truthdoesn't undo it.
孩子们喜欢他，而他名不副实
Kids love him and he's notwho they think he is.
那样不对
It's not right.
谁在乎他是否名副其实?
Who cares if he'swhat he says he is?
谁能名副其实?
Who the hell is?
如果爱基于一个谎言,那么是否就不是真感情呢?
If love's based on lies,does that mean it's nota real feeling?
难道就没有愉悦吗？
Doesn't bringthe same pleasure?
你还是在谈论病人吗?
Are we still talkingabout the patient?
你没骗过人吗?
Have you ever cheated?
我骗过
Well,I have.
你想惩罚他，你去做吧
You want to punish him,good for you.
但是你无法使爱他的人不同时受罚
But you can't do itwithout punishing the people who love him.
是因为你骗了你妻子吗?
Is that you justifiedlying to you wives?
我说了的
I always told them.
没有出血症状
Well,he's negativefor bleeds.
恭喜你，小蔡，是癌症
Congratulations,chase.It's cancer.
把他弄干净给肿瘤科送去，,是他们的事儿了
Clean him upand let oncology have him. It's their party now.
他不是癌症
He doesn't have cancer.
活检显示他是单纯性血红细胞先天萎缩
biopsy shows he's gotpure red cell aplasia.
没理由PRCA检查这么清楚
There's no way prca couldmanifest so suddenly.
除非是药物导致
Unless it's drug-induced.
他说没用EPO是说谎的
He's lying about not being on epo.
他干嘛说谎?
Why would he lie?
有什么关系?
What does it matter?
人们有成千的理由说谎
People liefor thousands of reasons,
但总要有理由
but there's alwaysa reason.
有趣的哲理，但与医学无关
Philosophically interesting,medically irrelevant.
除非他没说谎
Unless he's not lying.
你泄露消息了
You've got a leak.
传媒到处报道弗杰的故事
The press is all overthe jeff forster story.
机率虽小，但没准你们中有人愚蠢到从,自己的办公室打电话……
On the off-chance thatone of you was stupid enough to call from your own office,
我要提取你们的电话记录
I'm pulling your phone records.
包括手机记录
Including your cell phones.
我假设如果我能证实你无权如此作为
I assume if I point outthe fact that you have no rightto do that
你就会内疚的予以解释了
you'll interpret that as a sign of guilt.
威尔胡扯的
Wilson's chatty.
再加上他有两个妻子要供养
Plus he's gottwo ex-wives to support.
你想让我告诉他他被解雇了吗?
You want meto tell him he's fired?
在查到是谁的作为前,我会跟你们一起办公
Until we figure outwho's behind this,I'm sitting inwith you guys.
如果你们的道德跟4岁孩子一样,我就当你们是4岁一样对待
You have the ethicsof a four-year-old. I'm gonna treat youlike one.
一个律师坐我肩上,我怎么干医生的行当?
How am I supposedto practice medicine with a lawyersitting on my shoulder?
负责任的干
Responsibly.
你知道我不行
You know I can't do that.
卡梅伦
Cameron.
我没泄露
I'm not the leak.
某人曾告诉我所有人都说谎
Somebody once told methat everybody lies.
既然你是唯一一个知道他得癌的人……
And since you're the only people who know he has cancer--
他没得癌
he doesn't have cancer.
重点是你是他的医疗小组
the point is you're his medical team.
他威胁要诉讼
He's threatening to sue.
为什么卡梅伦放水说癌症?
Why would cameron leak cancer?
癌症又怎么会令他难看?
How does cancermake the guy look bad?
他用EPO
He's on epo.
你的贫血由单纯血红细胞萎缩造成
Your anemia is caused by pure red blood cellaplasia.
这会挺疼的，但我们要谈谈
This is gonna hurt,but we've gotta talk.
你到底干什么啊?
What the hellare you doing?
他会没事的
He'll be fine.
没准
Sort of.
我只是没时间看他写出答案来
I just don't have time to watch himwrite out answers.
Prca 有两种结果：急性、慢性
Prca comes in two varieties. Chronic and acute.
因为来势甚快，所以你是急性的
Since it came on fast,you have the acute version.
他没有癌症
He doesn't have cancer.
这是好消息
Is the good news.
坏消息是...
The bad new is...
裤子着火了
pants are on fire.
急性PRCA由药物导致,最常见的是EPO
Acute prca is causedby drugs. Most commonly,epo.
准备－－开拍！
Ready,and--action!
可我没用epo
But I haven't used epo.
好
Okay.
但这次表现更多愤怒
But this timewith more anger.
记住，这家伙可是在指控你欺诈
Remember,this guy'saccusing you of cheating.
我没用那些东西
I haven't used that stuff.
哦，我信了
Oh! Mwah!I believed it.
简单、纯情，你相信他吗?
It was simple. It was pure.Did you believe it?
我猜头一次试演就定人选太傻了
I guess it's silly to cast someone after the first audition.
你来表演一下如何?
Why don't you do a reading?
给我，他没用epo
Give me that.He doesn't do epo.
嗯，你觉得呢?
Hmm. What did you think?
我的意思是，很难
I mean,it's a differentway to go,
但是，我不知道，我就是不信
but I don't know,I just didn't buy it.
是她在给你注射吧?
Does she handleany of your injections?
你以为是我给他的吗?
You thinkI'm giving it to him?
给他做试演
Test him.
嗯，这主意真不错
Gee. That's a great idea.
我希望EPO不是那种注射6小时后,就查不出来的药品
I sure hope that epo'snot one of those drugs that's undetectableafter six hours.
嘿，你知道我们可以查什么吗?
Hey,you know whatwe can test for?
电话
Phone calls.
拿她的手机，按重播键
Take her cell phone, push the redial button.
连钱都会说你放水给报纸,泄露癌症的消息
Even money says you'll be connected to the newspaper thatleaked your cancer story.
好吧
Okay.
好吧，我该告诉你的
Okay,I should'vetold you.
跟比赛无关，杰
It's not just about the races,jeff.
事关你的形象，好吗?
It's about your image.Okay?
如果你能战胜癌症,那些赞助商会蜂拥而至的
If you come back from cancer,those sponsors will beall over you.
好吧，我搞砸了
Okay,so I messed up.
好吧，可我没给你epo
Okay. But I did notgive you epo.
那玩意会要了我的命
That stuff could kill me.
好了，饶了她吧
Come on,give her a break.
她只是尽力提升自己的事业而已
She's only doingwhat she has to do to advance her career.
你身上不也有那样的纹身吗?
Don't you have thattattooed on your tushie?
我不会做伤害你的事
I would neverdo anything to hurt you.
你要信谁?
Who are you gonna believe?
你多年信任的经纪人吗?
The manager you'vetrusted for years?
我上过大学
Pff! I've been to college.
你被炒了
You're fired.
好吧
Okay.
你把诊断，所有的事情
You're basing this wholediagnosis,everything,
都建立在我给他违禁药品的基础上
on the idea that I wasslipping him illegal drugs.
你会杀了他
You're gonna kill him.
如果豪斯医生那么确定,你为什么需要留医？
If dr. House is so sure,why do you need to stay?
他很谨慎
He's a very cautious man.
你呼吸状况好多了
You're breathing's better.
让强尼松发挥功效,好好睡觉吧
Let the prednisonedo its job. Get some sleep.
杰?
Jeff?
他的血红细胞读数下降到16%了
His red blood cell count plummeted to 16%.
他昏迷了，得唤醒他,还是不能移动双腿
He passed out,had to be resuscitated, and he still can'tmove his legs.
不可能啊
That's not possible.
药品该已经被冲出体外了
The drugs should be flushingout of his system.
如果不存在就无法消失
Can't leaveif they don't exist.
epo通常可以解释有他这种症状的人
The epo use explainsevery one of his symptoms.
他撒谎骗人，现在这些找上他了
He's been lyingand cheating, and now it's comingback to bite him.
那个假设的理论基础是,宇宙其实只是个位置而已
The only problem withthat theory is it's based on the assumption thatthe universe is a just place.
如果真是，那他的经纪人,就不会无由被炒
If it were,then his poor manager wouldn't have been firedfor no reason.
-兰伊顿,-他的肺没事
-Lambert-eaton. -His chest was clear.
那我们来做肌电图测试
so we run an electromyography test.
还是不能解释prca
You're stillnot explaining the prca.
现在血红细胞读数是多少?
What's his red count now?
我得输血使他到30
I had to give hima blood transfusion. He's back around 30.
他需要输血?
He needed a transfusion?
嗯，他失血，所以我想他需要输血
Well,he was losing blood,so I thoughtmaybe he needed blood.
快去扫描他的颈部
Go forth and scan his neck.
颈部?
His neck?
或者是用疑问句形式重复我说的话也可以
Or repeat everythingI say in question form.
她闯进诊所对我大喊大叫
She came into the clinicand yelled at me.
然后就离开了
Then she left,
然后又回来又喊了一通
then she came backand yelled some more.
嗯，喊叫
Hmm. Yelling.
没准是线索
That might be a clue.
我知道叫喊的意思
Well,I know whatthe yelling means.
是来来去去让我好奇
It's the coming and goingI find interesting.
-是不理智,-生气是不理智的
-It's not rational. -Anger's not rational.
有的生气是的
Some anger is.
她可以把我拉到一边,私下里跟我喊啊
She could'vepulled me aside, screamed at my privately.
她简单又好强
Her beef is simpleand well-founded.
但是失控了
But she wasout of control.
你觉得很有趣，是吧?
You're having fun,aren't you?
她冲我喊叫，我想知道原因
She's in my face.I need to know why.
专业原因
Professional reasons.
难道还有其他吗?
Oh. Why else?
你真认为这能欢喜结局吗?
Do you really thinkthis is going to end well?
对任何人而言?
For anyone?
这个完事后,我们再照个其他不相干的部位吧
After this,let's scan some other total random body parts.
赌50块，我们能有所发现
50 bucks sayswe find something.
发现什么?
[Scoffs]Find what?
没线索，我们查的是?
Don't have a clue.We on?
不
No way.
不，我们会发现的
No. We'll find something.
我们发现了一个胸腺瘤
We found a thymoma.
你怎么知道该查他的脖子?
How'd you knowto look in his neck?
胸腺瘤常出现在胸部
Thymomas usuallypresent in the chest.
我知道不在胸部
I knew it wasn'tin his chest.
他入院后我们一直在查胸
All we've donesince he checked in is look at his chest.
只有另一个理由没想到，有两种PRCA
Well,all the morereason not to think-- there aretwo types of prca.
急性的突发，慢性的需要时间
Acute comes on suddenly.Chronic takes its time.
我们因杰的发生在眼前就以为是急性的
We all thoughtjeff's was acute because it happenedright in front of us,
但如果是已经存在数月?甚至数年呢？
but what if it had been therefor months? Maybe years?
不应该，会使他无法比赛
there's no way. It would'vekept him from racing.
那么厉害的贫血，该需要经常输血
With that kind of anemia,he would've needed constant--
所以他输血红细胞
blood transfusions. Which he was getting in convenientblood doping form.
他在不知情的情况下那样治疗了
He was treating himselfwithout even knowing it.
半数以上的慢性PRCA有胸腺瘤
Up to half of patientswith chronic prca have a thymoma,
而一半以上有胸腺瘤的病人……
and up to half the patientswith a thymoma--
我一直都想干这个
I've always wantedto do this.
我不会好起来了
I'm not gettingany better.
那是否意味着……
Does that mean I'm--
你被治好了
You are healed.
起来走路吧
Rise and walk.
你疯了吗?
Are you insane?
在圣经中人们只说“是的，圣主”,然后立刻开始赞美
In the bible,they just say, "yes,lord," and then startright in on the praising.
你先说我得癌了
First you tell me I've got cancer,
然后说我的经纪人……
and then you tell me that my manager--
你干了什么?
What did you do?
不，你干了什么，圣主?
No. What do you do,lord?
胸腺瘤是长在胸腺的瘤子
Thymoma is a tumor on the thymus gland.
他有点懦弱，但却吊上个壮汉
He's a bit a wimp, but he hangs with the tough guys.
PRCA免疫系统疾病叫做肌无力
Prca and an auto-immunedisease called myasthenia gravis.
缺氧导致肌肉疲倦,包括呼吸系统和吞咽困难
Mg causes muscle fatigue, includingrespiratory problems and difficulty swallowing.
哦，能那么快就打败你吗?
Oh. And it can hit youthat fast?
治疗贫血就输血
The treatment for prcais blood transfusions.
治疗缺氧就给氧
The treatment for mgis hyperbaria.
你把这两样当日常保养供给
You were doing both as part of yourregular freak show.
你停止了就失控了
When you took a break,everything went to hell.
不是常态该有的状态
Which is not an uncommonreaction to jersey.
那么...
So...
我经纪人的事情
the whole thingwith my manager.
哦，不是的
Oops. No.
不是epo
No epo.
跟你做的事无关
This has nothingto do with anything you did.
你可以让她知道她没事
You can let her knowshe's in the clear.
我可以，或者……
I could. Or--
10%的耐克广告合同可是一大笔现金啊
Ten perfectof a nike contract is a hell ofa lot of cash.
上帝
God.
你不需要胸腺了，我们把它移除,其他都可以安排
You don't need your thymus. We take it out.Everything else is manageable.
可以安排？,我以为你已经把我治好了
Manageable? I thoughtyou just cured me.
哦，那只是诊断
Un-uh. This isjust diagnostic.
Tensilon 只能把症状从,缺氧中解脱5-6分钟
Tensilon erasesthe symptoms of mg for five or six minutes.
有时更短
Sometimes less.
这正是我创造了护士的原因
This is exactly whyI created nurses.
清理3号走廊
Clean up on aisle three!
如果你来搜我的办公室
If you've come to search my office,
你该再迟10分钟，我就走了
you should wait ten minutes.I'll be out of your hair.
给，由我的钱包开始
Here. Start with my purse.
给我留点薄荷糖
Just save me some mints.
你想知道什么？,我跟马克的性生活吗？
What do you want to know?My sex life with mark?
把你腿搞折的内疚？
My guilt over cripplingyour damn leg?
还是因为你不是放水的人而得意?
Or are you just here to gloatbecause you weren't the leak?
我想道歉
I want to apologize.
也许我...
Maybe I've...
惩罚你太久了
been punishing youfor a little too long.
而或许你也在惩罚我
And maybe you've beenpunishing me.
如果我们要一起工作
If we're gonnawork together,
我需要知道
I need to know.
你是恨我还是爱我?
Do you hate meor do you love me?
要不，我看我们有问题了
Either way,I thinkwe've got a problem.
我对你爱恨交加
I hate you.And I love you.
而我爱马克
And I love mark.
而你不恨他
And you don't hate him.
不
No.
那我们怎么办?
So what do we do?
我们应对吧
We deal with each other.
对
Hmph. Right.
这计划至今进展顺利
That plans been workinggreat so far.
会更好，更容易的
It'll get better.It'll get easier.
为何?
Why?
不知道，我心理医生告诉我的
I don't know. That's whatmy therapist tells me.
他每两周需要一次输血
he needs blood transfusions every two weeks,
意思是他要输多少都可以了
which means he can dopeall he wants.
有医生的许可
He's a got a doctor's pass.
是医用的
It's medicinal.
他得逞了
He got away with it.
他骗人还赢了比赛
He cheated and won a game.
生命比谁赢更复杂
Life's more complicated than who getsto the finish line first.
我爱上了丈夫最好的朋友
I fell in love withmy husband's best friend.
快结束的时候，我整天在医院
Near the end,I wasat the hospital every day,
乔会下班后过来
and joe would come byafter work.
我们散布试图解决问题
We'd go for walks and try to talk each other through it.
我们有点粘上了
We kind of clung onto each other.
我妻子...
My wife...
并没要死，她甚至没病
wasn't dying. She wasn't even sick.
根本没事
Everything was fine.
我遇上了……
I met someone who--ahem.
让我觉得有趣
Made me feel...funny.
好
Good.
我不想让那感情走
And I didn't wantto let that feeling go.
发生到你的事...
What happened to you...
哪有人能单独承担?
how can anyonego through that alone?
你无法控制情绪
You can't controlyour emotions.
不
No.
只是行为
Just your actions.
你没那么干吧？跟他睡觉？
You didn't do it,did you? You didn't sleep with him.
我无法单独生活
I couldn't havelived with myself.
你会为自己的生存能力而惊讶
You'd be surprisedwhat you can live with.
我需要你打开门
I need youto open a door.
不允许
Not allowed.
我今天在这做治疗来着,把拐杖落下了
Yeah,I was havingtherapy in here today, and I left my cane.
对不起
Sorry.
老兄...
Dude...
我是瘸子
I'm crippled.